<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Xianmin's Blog</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/</link><description>Recent content on Xianmin's Blog</description><follow_challenge><feedId>57631672911801359</feedId><userId>51859777516028928</userId></follow_challenge><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 14:41:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.xianmin.org/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Weekly Journal of a 33-year-old Unemployed Rural Programmer's Self-Help Journey (Part 3) - Finding My Position</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/003/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 14:41:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/003/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Xianmin, 33 years old, a programmer living in the countryside, unemployed for two years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This week, my income broke through a thousand yuan, achieving a milestone goal.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="this-weeks-self-help-actions">This Week&amp;rsquo;s Self-Help Actions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The first four days of this week were busy.&lt;br>
I had to wear multiple hats - salesperson, customer service, after-sales support, and writer, doing everything myself.&lt;br>
I won&amp;rsquo;t elaborate much on computer skills as they&amp;rsquo;re my bread and butter.&lt;br>
Moreover, I found that my jack-of-all-trades technical skills are particularly suitable for small jobs that professionals might overlook.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Being needed gives a sense of value.&lt;br>
On my busiest day, I communicated with more than ten clients while handling four tasks simultaneously.&lt;br>
Although the money earned isn&amp;rsquo;t much, it&amp;rsquo;s at least a validation of my personal labor.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="lets-talk-about-failed-cases">Let&amp;rsquo;s Talk About Failed Cases&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The first one was a remote printing job.&lt;br>
The client was very nice to me, first giving me a small task with a tip, then assigning me this job.&lt;br>
As luck would have it, I had two unfinished projects at the time.&lt;br>
After pondering for two hours, I realized remote printing wasn&amp;rsquo;t that simple, and with other ongoing projects, I had to refund the payment.&lt;br>
It was quite awkward, as it consumed the trust placed in me.&lt;br>
Well, accepting payment is a guarantee of trust - if you don&amp;rsquo;t have time or confidence, don&amp;rsquo;t take the money carelessly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second case was developing a webpage modification plugin.&lt;br>
The client described it simply - just changing 1 to 2 in a table on a webpage, so I quoted a low price.&lt;br>
Later, I discovered it was a foreign government website, and just the key login took over an hour, with modifications being not so straightforward.&lt;br>
I had to refund again.&lt;br>
This client was quite cunning, describing an apparently easy task that was actually much more complex.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As for successful cases, I won&amp;rsquo;t say much, but here&amp;rsquo;s one touching feedback:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&amp;ldquo;What I couldn&amp;rsquo;t solve in a week, you fixed in an hour. I&amp;rsquo;ll come directly to you next time.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="phase-summary">Phase Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In February, after the Spring Festival, I reassessed my situation.&lt;br>
I clarified my direction: focusing on freelancing to solve survival needs first,&lt;br>
with content writing and personal projects as my second trajectory for personal development.&lt;br>
Although this choice remains high-risk, it&amp;rsquo;s shaped by past experiences - there&amp;rsquo;s no good or bad about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Looking at the results from the past three weeks, this year&amp;rsquo;s short-term self-help plan seems feasible.&lt;br>
As long as freelancing can solve survival needs, I don&amp;rsquo;t need to look for a job for now.&lt;br>
I&amp;rsquo;ve now repositioned myself as: &lt;strong>Your Personal Technical Handyman.&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
In other words, I&amp;rsquo;m like a temporary computer technology plumber.&lt;br>
Can&amp;rsquo;t fix a bug? I&amp;rsquo;ll repair it; Can&amp;rsquo;t set up development environment? I&amp;rsquo;ll help remotely;&lt;br>
Don&amp;rsquo;t want to handle legacy projects? No problem, let me do it; Need a small application? I can make it in three days.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>For larger projects, unless particularly interesting, I probably won&amp;rsquo;t consider them for now.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Some reflections:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Efficient communication, no prolonged battles. Directly reject grey industry requests. End conversations early with those seeking cheap labor. No need to continue talking if requirements and budget aren&amp;rsquo;t clear within 10 messages.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Organize and master communication skills. Friends say I&amp;rsquo;m too rigid - yes, you can see it in my writing style, my EQ is quite low. But in sales and customer service, attitude and awareness are needed, so I&amp;rsquo;ll have to let AI teach me how to communicate with clients.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Improve pricing skills. This can only come from experience. Some small jobs are simple but take 3-4 hours, making low prices very unprofitable. Some issues could be resolved earlier through prior communication.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="this-weeks-income">This Week&amp;rsquo;s Income&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th style="text-align: left">Date&lt;/th>
&lt;th style="text-align: left">Description&lt;/th>
&lt;th style="text-align: left">Duration&lt;/th>
&lt;th style="text-align: left">Amount&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">0224&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">Website Setup&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">2h&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">50&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">0224&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">Enterprise App&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">2d&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">600&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">0225&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">Bug Fix&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">1.5h&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">80&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">0225&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">Feature Addition&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">2h&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">80&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">0225&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">Remote Support&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">1.5h&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">80&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">0226&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">Last Week&amp;rsquo;s Payment&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">0&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">450&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">0226&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">Enterprise App&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">1d&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">300&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">0227&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">Website Setup&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">2h&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">80&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Total: 1720 yuan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The duration statistics above are rough calculations, as communication usually takes considerable time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I feel that publicizing income might not be very appropriate, so I might reconsider doing so in the future&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="closing-words">Closing Words&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you have any thoughts about this middle-aged unemployed programmer&amp;rsquo;s self-help journey, please feel free to leave a comment, thank you! ðŸ™&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Weekly: 33-years-old Unemployed Programmer's Self-rescue(2) - Writing Academic Papers</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/002/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 00:31:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/002/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Xianmin, 33 years old, a programmer living in the countryside, unemployed for two years.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="this-weeks-self-help-actions">This Week&amp;rsquo;s Self-Help Actions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Last weekend, I took on a writing job for an academic paper about machine learning.&lt;br>
I don&amp;rsquo;t know much about machine learning, but I can write some Python.&lt;br>
With AI assistance available, I boldly accepted the project.&lt;br>
Looking back now, it was a bit presumptuous.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I spent four full days coding. During the first two days with little progress, I almost gave up.&lt;br>
On the third day, things started moving forward, but hardware limitations and AI debugging loops became challenging.&lt;br>
The main issue was my lack of understanding. When asking AI for explanations, I could read every word but couldn&amp;rsquo;t grasp why things were done certain ways.&lt;br>
I didn&amp;rsquo;t have time to study the fundamentals, so I had to push through with countless new AI conversations and experiments.&lt;br>
The most troublesome part was the loss of context - I had to keep summarizing our previous progress for the AI.&lt;br>
Nevertheless, I managed to achieve the experimental objectives, with only one day left before the client&amp;rsquo;s deadline.&lt;br>
On the final day, I hurriedly produced a paper of nearly 20,000 words, of course, with AI assistance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I submitted the work, I felt completely drained of energy for the entire week.&lt;br>
This was my first time writing an academic paper and my first time coding for machine learning.&lt;br>
This job wasn&amp;rsquo;t just stepping out of my comfort zone - it was like rolling in uncomfortable darkness.&lt;br>
Although I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely satisfied with the quality of the paper and code, at least I delivered something to the client.&lt;br>
This money wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy to earn!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In retrospect, for a professional, this would have been a two-day job.&lt;br>
One day for coding, one day for writing - equivalent to 500 per day, making it somewhat feasible.&lt;br>
My main challenge was being completely unfamiliar with machine learning, which requires time to learn.&lt;br>
I estimate it would take two weeks to grasp the basic knowledge.&lt;br>
But I&amp;rsquo;m unsure what else I could do with machine learning knowledge besides writing papers.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="this-weeks-income">This Week&amp;rsquo;s Income&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Completed 2 small orders +110 yuan;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="closing-words">Closing Words&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Have you had experience in tutoring academic paper writing?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Do you think machine learning is worth investing time to learn?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>If you have any thoughts about a middle-aged unemployed programmer&amp;rsquo;s self-help journey, please leave a comment. Thank you! ðŸ™&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Weekly: 33-years-old Unemployed Programmer's Self-rescue (1)</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/001/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 02:23:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/001/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello, I&amp;rsquo;m Xianmin, 33 years old, a programmer living in the countryside, unemployed for two years.&lt;br>
I have a middle school education, self-taught programming, and started my career in Shenzhen.&lt;br>
Later, I ran a youth hostel in Lijiang for 7 years, which closed due to the pandemic and other reasons.&lt;br>
Not wanting to return to big cities, I did remote work for over a year.&lt;br>
Two years ago, I went traveling with my girlfriend, and my programming work was interrupted again.&lt;br>
During the travels, I helped my girlfriend with social media accounts, shooting videos, and writing content.&lt;br>
Last year showed some improvement, but the income wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough to cover even half of one person&amp;rsquo;s expenses.&lt;br>
The dream of being financially supported by content creation fell through.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This year, to solve survival problems, I must make some changes.&lt;br>
Let&amp;rsquo;s start with this weekly journal, recording my self-rescue actions from the past week.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-save-myself">How to Save Myself&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Last year, I briefly tried the independent development path, creating a reader application called EvoReader.&lt;br>
But after launch, there was little feedback, and many features weren&amp;rsquo;t completed, so I paused the project.&lt;br>
Since I hadn&amp;rsquo;t figured out how to promote or monetize it, continuing development might only increase sunk costs.&lt;br>
I lacked confidence in this project.&lt;br>
Then I started learning and understanding how other independent developers do it, how they make money.&lt;br>
The reality is much harder than I imagined, with most independent developers&amp;rsquo; works disappearing in the vast internet ocean.&lt;br>
Even for the few that stand out, monetization is extremely difficult.&lt;br>
Succeeding in this path requires exceptionally high comprehensive abilities, and it&amp;rsquo;s time-consuming with uncertain results.&lt;br>
I urgently need to make money now, so this path can only be a side project in my spare time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ruling-out-big-city-job-search">Ruling Out Big City Job Search&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Having lived in rural Yunnan for many years, I&amp;rsquo;m too used to freedom and can&amp;rsquo;t return to big cities.&lt;br>
With my resume, job hunting would be extremely challenging.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="finding-remote-work">Finding Remote Work&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Usually, only small startup teams might need a versatile programmer like me.&lt;br>
This is relatively suitable but requires the right opportunity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="freelancing">Freelancing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Last year, I took some small projects on a platform, which proved to be a viable path.&lt;br>
However, there were too few projects with low rates.&lt;br>
I hadn&amp;rsquo;t accumulated enough experience, having had many choices before, I didn&amp;rsquo;t put much effort into freelancing.&lt;br>
I used to avoid projects I wasn&amp;rsquo;t interested in, but now I have to change my mindset.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Freelancing provides simple and direct feedback - each project means income.&lt;br>
With AI support, efficiency has greatly improved.&lt;br>
This is my main path for short-term self-rescue.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="content-writing">Content Writing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve had a personal website for a long time, which helped me find jobs and meet new friends.&lt;br>
But, well, the output was too little, update frequency too low, mainly because I was too lazy.&lt;br>
This path serves freelancing in the short term and potential personal works in the long term.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="writing-more-utility-applications">Writing More Utility Applications&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve now mastered an AI development process for personal use.&lt;br>
Development efficiency skyrockets as long as I have ideas.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="this-weeks-accomplishments">This Week&amp;rsquo;s Accomplishments&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Added Google Ads to my personal website. Well, although I know the revenue won&amp;rsquo;t be much, in the current situation, I have to try every direction;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Opened a WeChat Official Account - Cognitive Leap Plan;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated WeChat Official Account and Xiaohongshu, I must take this step, though I feel I&amp;rsquo;m a hundred steps behind others;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Compiled a list of remote work websites;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Joined 3 freelancing groups (still late to realize this);&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="this-weeks-income">This Week&amp;rsquo;s Income&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Completed 1 small project + 98 yuan;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Completed 1 small project + 149 yuan;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>More small projects like these, please&amp;hellip;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="closing-words">Closing Words&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you have any thoughts on this middle-aged unemployed programmer&amp;rsquo;s self-rescue action, please leave a comment, thank you! ðŸ™&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why I Choose Vivaldi as My Primary Browser</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2025/why-choose-vivaldi-browser-vs-chrome/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 12:57:01 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2025/why-choose-vivaldi-browser-vs-chrome/</guid><description>&lt;p>I used Chrome for many years. It was fast, had plenty of extensions, and made web debugging convenient - meeting all my needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, one day, Chrome suddenly changed its UI style, making it uncomfortable to use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main issue was the change in the right-click menu, where menu options had larger spacing and required scrolling when there were too many options.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Initially, I could revert to the old UI style through &lt;code>chrome://flags/&lt;/code>, but later that option was completely removed.&lt;br>
While searching online for new solutions, I came across someone mentioning Vivaldi.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I decided to give it a try.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="Vivaldi Browser" src="https://www.xianmin.org/post/2025/why-choose-vivaldi-browser-vs-chrome/vivaldi.jpg" title="Vivaldi Browser Interface">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Switching to Vivaldi wasn&amp;rsquo;t difficult at all since it&amp;rsquo;s also a Chromium-based browser that can directly install extensions from the Chrome Web Store.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I migrated my bookmarks, installed my frequently used extensions, and most of my needs were met.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Vivaldi&amp;rsquo;s right-click menu can be switched back to the old style, which was my initial motivation for using it.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vivaldi adds many extra features on top of Chromium.&lt;br>
I didn&amp;rsquo;t use them much at first, but later discovered that some features were quite useful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are several features I use most frequently:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Sidebar Tab Management.&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>When you have many tabs open, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to see their titles or find the tab you want to switch to.&lt;br>
The sidebar window manager makes it convenient.&lt;br>
It&amp;rsquo;s easy to switch between tabs and perform operations like deletion and moving tabs.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Multi-page Tiling.&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Sometimes you want to display two tabs in one window simultaneously, eliminating the need to switch back and forth.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Image Loading Toggle.&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Some content-heavy websites have too many images when I only need to read the text.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="4">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Full Webpage Screenshot.&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>The built-in webpage screenshot tool is convenient to operate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although some Chrome extensions can achieve the above functions, Vivaldi integrates them into the browser, providing a smoother experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As for Vivaldi&amp;rsquo;s other features like the built-in email client and RSS reader, I don&amp;rsquo;t use them, so I won&amp;rsquo;t comment on those.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Copy Unblocker - A Userscript to Remove Website Copy Restrictions</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2025/userscript-copy-unblocker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 13:36:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2025/userscript-copy-unblocker/</guid><description>&lt;p>Some websites prevent text copying. I previously used the SuperCopy Chrome extension to bypass website copy restrictions. Later, I discovered that this extension was involved in traffic hijacking behavior: &lt;a href="https://www.v2ex.com/t/1084504">Chrome Extension with 600K Users Contains Malicious Code - V2EX&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, I decided to have AI help me write a script instead.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Project Repository: &lt;a href="https://github.com/xianmin/userscript-copy-unblocker">xianmin/userscript-copy-unblocker: Automatically removes copy restrictions&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="userscript-copy-unblocker">userscript-copy-unblocker&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>userscript-copy-unblocker is a userscript that automatically removes copy restrictions from web pages, allowing you to freely copy text content.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-use">How to Use&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Install a browser extension:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Chrome: &lt;a href="https://chromewebstore.google.com/detail/tampermonkey/dhdgffkkebhmkfjojejmpbldmpobfkfo">Tampermonkey&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Firefox: &lt;a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/greasemonkey/">Greasemonkey&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Install the Copy Unblocker script: &lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/xianmin/userscript-copy-unblocker/refs/heads/master/copy-unblocker.user.js">Click to Install&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Visit supported websites, and the script will automatically remove copy restrictions&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="features">Features&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Automatically removes webpage copy restrictions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enables text selection and right-click menu&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removes overlay layers that block content&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Supports keyboard shortcuts (Ctrl+C/Cmd+C)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="adding-support-for-new-websites">Adding Support for New Websites&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you want the script to support new websites, you can:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Submit an &lt;a href="https://github.com/xianmin/userscript-copy-unblocker/issues">Issue&lt;/a> on GitHub&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Or modify the script directly by adding new &lt;code>@match&lt;/code> rules at the top of the code&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="privacy-and-security">Privacy and Security&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Runs entirely on the client-side&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No data collection&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open-source and transparent&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="additional-references">Additional References&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/WindRunnerMax/TKScript">WindRunnerMax/TKScript: Userscripts &amp;amp; Browser Extensions&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.runningcheese.com/enable-copy">3 Methods to Solve 99% of Web Page Copy Issues - Running Cheese&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Multilingual Hugo Blog - How to Elegantly Manage Markdown Content</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2024/hugo-multilingual-blog-structure/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 11:04:39 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2024/hugo-multilingual-blog-structure/</guid><description>&lt;p>This website is built with &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo&lt;/a> and deployed on Github.&lt;br>
To publish a new article, I only need to edit the Markdown file and upload it to Github, where GitHub Actions automatically generates the webpage for me.&lt;br>
The entire process is so simple that I can update blog posts even from my phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As the number of blog posts increased, managing Markdown files became a challenge.&lt;br>
Previously, without good organizational habits, I placed all files directly in the &lt;code>post/&lt;/code> directory.&lt;br>
Later, as files accumulated, I created subdirectories like &lt;code>post/2024/&lt;/code> within the &lt;code>post/&lt;/code> directory.&lt;br>
The URL of a blog post is related to its file location. For example, a blog post at &lt;code>post/2024/example.md&lt;/code> would have the URL &lt;code>/post/2024/example/&lt;/code>.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>To avoid changing the URLs of published posts&lt;/strong>, I left the old Markdown files in their original locations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="my blog old post structure" src="https://www.xianmin.org/image/post/2024/hugo-multilingual-blog-structure.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="multilingual-sites">Multilingual Sites&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Hugo has supported multilingual sites for many years, and I had considered creating an English version of my site, but translation was always an issue.&lt;br>
With the advancement of AI in recent years, translation quality has improved significantly.&lt;br>
Recently, I had the idea to create a multilingual site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Hugo, for multilingual sites, if you want a blog post to have multiple language versions, you typically need to create corresponding language versions of the md file.&lt;br>
For example, the English version of &lt;code>blog.md&lt;/code> would be &lt;code>blog.en.md&lt;/code>, and other languages follow the same pattern.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Without a proper organization scheme, as time goes by, the number of files in the &lt;code>post/&lt;/code> directory would keep increasing, making it increasingly difficult to manage.&lt;br>
Additionally, modifying blog post URLs would become more complicated in the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Therefore, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to address &lt;strong>how to organize files in the post/ directory&lt;/strong> early on.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="need-for-a-proper-organization-scheme">Need for a Proper Organization Scheme&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Based on my past experience, creating a new folder for each year like &lt;code>post/2022/&lt;/code>, &lt;code>post/2023/&lt;/code>, &lt;code>post/2024/&lt;/code>, etc., is generally sufficient for my needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For multilingual sites, placing all &lt;code>blog.md&lt;/code> and &lt;code>blog.language.md&lt;/code> files in one folder isn&amp;rsquo;t ideal for management.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s better to keep all language versions of the same blog post in one folder, such as &lt;code>post/2024/blog/blog.md&lt;/code>, &lt;code>post/2024/blog/blog.language.md&lt;/code>, etc. However, this would result in URLs like &lt;code>/post/2024/blog/blog&lt;/code>, which is redundant. To address this, Hugo provides a &lt;code>slug&lt;/code> parameter that can modify the final part of the URL path.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, &lt;strong>to facilitate sorting, I add dates to the beginning of folder names&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, this article&amp;rsquo;s directory structure looks like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight-container">
&lt;button class="copy-code-btn outline">Copy&lt;/button>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>post
â”œâ”€â”€â”€2017
â”œâ”€â”€â”€2018
â”œâ”€â”€â”€2019
â”œâ”€â”€â”€2020
â”œâ”€â”€â”€2021
â”œâ”€â”€â”€2022
â”œâ”€â”€â”€2023
â””â”€â”€â”€2024
â”œâ”€â”€â”€20240920-jane-theme-v3-major-update
â””â”€â”€â”€20241105-hugo-multilingual-blog-structure
hugo-multilingual-blog-structure.en.md
hugo-multilingual-blog-structure.md&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The &lt;code>Front Matter&lt;/code> structure of this article looks like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight-container">
&lt;button class="copy-code-btn outline">Copy&lt;/button>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>---
title: Hugo å¤šè¯­è¨€åšå®¢æ­å»ºï¼Œå¦‚ä½•ä¼˜é›…åœ°ç®¡ç†å¤šè¯­è¨€ Markdown å†…å®¹
date: 2024-11-05T11:04:39+08:00
draft: true
tags:
- Hugo
- å¤šè¯­è¨€
- åšå®¢æ­å»º
- ç½‘ç«™ä¼˜åŒ–
- æ–‡ä»¶ç®¡ç†
- URL ç»“æž„
- å†…å®¹ç®¡ç†
- ç«™ç‚¹è¿ç§»
categories:
- è®¡ç®—æœº
lastmod: 2024-11-05T11:04:39+08:00
slug: ../hugo-multilingual-blog-structure/
summary: æœ¬æ–‡ä»‹ç»ä½¿ç”¨ Hugo æ­å»ºå¤šè¯­è¨€ç«™ç‚¹åŽçš„æ–‡ä»¶ç»„ç»‡æ–¹æ¡ˆã€URL ç»“æž„ä¼˜åŒ–ï¼Œä»¥åŠå¦‚ä½•å®‰å…¨è¿ç§»çŽ°æœ‰åšå®¢å†…å®¹ã€‚é€‚åˆæƒ³è¦æž„å»ºå¤šè¯­è¨€åšå®¢çš„ Hugo ç”¨æˆ·å‚è€ƒã€‚
---&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="organizing-old-markdown-files">Organizing Old Markdown Files&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With a proper organization scheme in place, we should reorganize existing files and place them in appropriate locations.&lt;br>
It&amp;rsquo;s particularly important to &lt;strong>avoid URL changes&lt;/strong>. Hugo provides a &lt;code>url&lt;/code> parameter that can set URLs to fixed values.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s my process:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step 1: Delete the &lt;code>public/&lt;/code> directory, generate a new &lt;code>public/&lt;/code> based on existing blog posts, and rename it to &lt;code>public_old/&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step 2: Transfer files one by one, adding the original &lt;code>url&lt;/code> address to transferred files.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step 3: After completing the transfer, regenerate the &lt;code>public/&lt;/code> directory.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step 4: Compare &lt;code>public/sitemap.xml&lt;/code> and &lt;code>public_old/sitemap.xml&lt;/code> to check if URLs are consistent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step 5: Use &lt;code>Beyond Compare&lt;/code> to check if &lt;code>public/&lt;/code> and &lt;code>public_old/&lt;/code> are consistent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When manually modifying URLs, also pay attention to URL case sensitivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="references">References&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/content-management/multilingual/">Multilingual mode | Hugo&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/content-management/urls/">URL management | Hugo&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Hugo-Theme-Jane V3 Major Update</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2024/hugo-theme-jane-v3-major-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 06:56:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2024/hugo-theme-jane-v3-major-update/</guid><description>&lt;p>Project homepage: &lt;a href="https://github.com/xianmin/hugo-theme-jane">https://github.com/xianmin/hugo-theme-jane&lt;/a> .&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="update-content">Update Content&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Using &lt;a href="https://picocss.com/">Pico CSS&lt;/a> as the color scheme, with switchable theme colors and dark/light mode support.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Custom homepage.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added STYLE SETTINGS, located in /assets/sass/_settings.scss&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deprecated Category page, merged into Archive page.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Since there are many modifications, some areas are still not perfect. Thank you for your understanding!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="customize-your-homepage">Customize Your Homepage&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The original homepage was a paginated article list, which could be somewhat monotonous. Now you can have a more personalized homepage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Copy &lt;code>/exampleSite/content/_index.md&lt;/code> to your website&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code>/content/_index.md&lt;/code> and modify the parameters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For multilingual sites, create similar &lt;code>_index.language.md&lt;/code> files, such as &lt;code>_index.zh-cn.md&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="personalize-your-website-through-style-settings">Personalize Your Website Through STYLE SETTINGS&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Copy &lt;code>/assets/sass/_settings.scss&lt;/code> and &lt;code>/assets/sass/_custom.scss&lt;/code> to your website&amp;rsquo;s root directory (Note: path names and file names must match).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Modify variables in &lt;code>_settings.scss&lt;/code> and add custom styles in &lt;code>/assets/sass/_custom.scss&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="upgrading-from-old-version-to-v3">Upgrading from Old Version to v3&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Due to the new version using the latest Sass language features, Dart Sass needs to be installed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Installation guide can be found in the official documentation: &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/hugo-pipes/transpile-sass-to-css/#dart-sass">https://gohugo.io/hugo-pipes/transpile-sass-to-css/#dart-sass&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re using CI/CD automation tools, remember to install Dart Sass as well: &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/hugo-pipes/transpile-sass-to-css/#installing-in-a-production-environment">https://gohugo.io/hugo-pipes/transpile-sass-to-css/#installing-in-a-production-environment&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note: You might encounter some compatibility issues after upgrading. If you face any difficulties, feel free to open an issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="theme-development-philosophy">Theme Development Philosophy&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>No &lt;code>node_modules&lt;/code>, fewer dependencies mean easier maintenance&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Encouraging users to modify the theme according to their preferences for a more personalized website&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reading experience is always the top priority&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deploy once, focus on writing, no more tinkering&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="afterword">Afterword&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using this website theme for seven years. Except for frequent changes in the first year, it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been modified much since then.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve always believed that for personal blogs, the written content is the most important, and as for the website style, it just needs to be acceptable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This major revision was a sudden inspiration to completely change the color scheme and upgrade the Hugo version while at it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I hope users will enjoy it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Swapping Ctrl and CapsLock Keys in Windows</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2022/windows-keyboard-remap-ctrl-capslock-powershell/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2022/windows-keyboard-remap-ctrl-capslock-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;code>Ctrl&lt;/code> key, being a common modifier for most software shortcuts, is quite inconveniently positioned on the keyboard. Meanwhile, the &lt;code>CapsLock&lt;/code> key, which is rarely used, occupies a prime location on the keyboard. Over my years of computer usage, swapping the positions of &lt;code>Ctrl&lt;/code> and &lt;code>CapsLock&lt;/code> keys has significantly improved my comfort and efficiency when using keyboard shortcuts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s how to swap these two keys using PowerShell commands (must be run as administrator):&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight-container">
&lt;button class="copy-code-btn outline">Copy&lt;/button>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>$hexified = &amp;#34;00,00,00,00,00,00,00,00,03,00,00,00,1d,00,3a,00,3a,00,1d,00,00,00,00,00&amp;#34;.Split(&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;) | % { &amp;#34;0x$_&amp;#34;};
$kbLayout = &amp;#39;HKLM:\System\CurrentControlSet\Control\Keyboard Layout&amp;#39;;
New-ItemProperty -Path $kbLayout -Name &amp;#34;Scancode Map&amp;#34; -PropertyType Binary -Value ([byte[]]$hexified);&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="references">References&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/joshschmelzle/5e88dabc71014d7427ff01bca3fed33d">Remap Caps Lock to Control on Windows 10&lt;/a> - This link provides information about mapping CapsLock to Ctrl, rather than swapping them.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>