<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Xianmin's Blog</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Xianmin's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 15:06:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Entrepreneurs Have No Holidays | Remote IT Concierge Startup Weekly (12)</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/012/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 15:05:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/012/</guid><description>This week I reflect on my current startup status and explore the challenges in content creation and product direction. On the entrepreneurial journey, there are no holidays, but direction is more important than effort.</description></item><item><title>No More Tasks | Remote Tech Manager Startup Weekly (10)</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/010/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 16:25:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/010/</guid><description>This week I finally completed backlogged projects and had free time for personal development. As a remote tech manager, I developed a VSCode extension that formats Markdown content for WeChat Official Accounts with one click. This solves the hassle of switching between multiple applications—from VSCode editing to third-party rendering to publishing on WeChat. While similar web applications exist, a VSCode plugin better fits developers&amp;rsquo; workflow. The extension is expected to be released next week.</description></item><item><title>A Powerful Tool for English Output | Remote IT Concierge Startup Weekly (9)</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/009/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 14:59:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/009/</guid><description>This week, I developed inpot-desktop based on the open-source project Pot, focusing on translating Chinese to English. Traditional translation processes are cumbersome, with most tools focusing on translating foreign languages to native languages rather than vice versa. inpot-desktop optimizes user experience by solving pain points such as source text loss during window switching and slow translation window response, providing a convenient and efficient translation tool for international communication.</description></item><item><title>Git Archive: Practical Guide for Efficient Packaging and Project Delivery</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2025/git-archive-tutorial-project-packaging/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 10:00:56 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2025/git-archive-tutorial-project-packaging/</guid><description>Git Archive: A powerful tool for efficiently packaging source code, making project delivery more professional. This article details how to use the git archive command to automatically exclude the .git directory and files in .gitignore, eliminating the need for manual filtering and generating clean project archives with a single command. Includes a useful PowerShell function that helps Windows users easily create standardized release packages. Compared to traditional compression tools, git archive is not only more efficient but also ensures consistency and professionalism in code delivery. An essential project delivery skill for developers.</description></item><item><title>Remote IT Concierge Startup Weekly (7) - Order Explosion</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/007/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 15:23:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/007/</guid><description>This week was filled with orders ranging from technical consulting, AI programming education, to project internationalization, Docker deployment, and ECharts visualization. As a self-taught programmer, I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered that technical breadth is highly practical in the freelance market, offering limited income but greater freedom. I share insights on solving technical challenges, pricing strategies, and reflect on whether programmers should focus on technical depth or expand their breadth.</description></item><item><title>Remote IT Concierge Startup Weekly (8) - Having Work Keeps the Mind at Ease</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/008/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 15:23:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/008/</guid><description>As a remote tech butler, this week I established a half-day cooperation with an outsourcing company, achieving a win-win situation. Through this experience, I deeply understood the principle of &amp;ldquo;having work keeps the mind at ease,&amp;rdquo; which I break down into two key dimensions, &amp;ldquo;having skills&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;having clients.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Remote IT Concierge Startup Weekly (6) - First Consulting Business</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/006/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 06:39:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/006/</guid><description>In the sixth week of my remote technical butler startup, I welcomed my first consulting business, exchanging thoughts on life and technical issues with a soon-to-graduate college student. This experience made me realize everyone can provide valuable consultation. This article shares my understanding of &amp;ldquo;margin of safety,&amp;rdquo; how to deal with career confusion, and thoughts on packaging consulting services into products.</description></item><item><title>Remote IT Concierge Startup Weekly (5) - Solving Big Problems with Small Investment</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/005/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 18:07:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/005/</guid><description>This week, I shifted from &amp;ldquo;self-rescue&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;entrepreneurship,&amp;rdquo; establishing my position as a Remote IT Concierge. Currently focusing on selective project acceptance while restarting my personal product development plan, steadily moving towards creating profitable products.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Journal of a 33-Year-Old Unemployed Rural Programmer's Self-Help Journey (4) - AI Efficiency, Income ¥1410</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/004/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 05:50:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/004/</guid><description>This article chronicles the self-help journey of a 33-year-old unemployed rural programmer. Through freelance projects including enterprise spreadsheet automation and Vue to React conversion, leveraging AI tools to improve work efficiency, he completed 8 orders earning ¥1410 in one week. The article shares experiences in remote freelancing, AI-assisted programming insights, and the importance of building client relationships, providing reference for programmers aspiring to freelance work.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Journal of a 33-year-old Unemployed Rural Programmer's Self-Help Journey (3) - Finding My Position</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/003/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 14:41:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/003/</guid><description>This article documents the third week of a 33-year-old unemployed rural programmer&amp;rsquo;s self-help journey. The author achieved weekly earnings over 1000 yuan through freelancing and established his position as a &amp;rsquo;technical handyman&amp;rsquo;. The article shares failed cases in remote printing and web development, summarizes experiences in efficient communication, improving speech skills, and pricing strategies, and displays real freelancing income details. This is a valuable experience sharing for programmers who want to achieve freelance work through technical skills.</description></item><item><title>Weekly: 33-years-old Unemployed Programmer's Self-rescue(2) - Writing Academic Papers</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/002/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 00:31:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/002/</guid><description>A real experience of a 33-year-old unemployed programmer taking on his first machine learning paper project, documenting his 4-day journey from zero knowledge to delivery.</description></item><item><title>Weekly: 33-years-old Unemployed Programmer's Self-rescue (1)</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/001/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 02:23:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/001/</guid><description>A true self-rescue record of a 33-year-old unemployed programmer, from a Shenzhen programmer to a Lijiang hostel owner, and then to remote work. This article details how a middle-aged programmer seeks new career paths in rural areas through remote freelancing, content creation, and independent development. It&amp;rsquo;s a story about how tech professionals can save themselves, as well as a practical guide for career transition.</description></item><item><title>Why I Choose Vivaldi as My Primary Browser</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2025/why-choose-vivaldi-browser-vs-chrome/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 12:57:01 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2025/why-choose-vivaldi-browser-vs-chrome/</guid><description>As a Chromium-based browser, Vivaldi not only offers perfect compatibility with Chrome extensions but also provides more user-friendly interface customization, powerful tab management, multi-page tiling, and other unique features. This article compares the user experience between Vivaldi and Chrome in detail to help you find the most suitable primary browser.</description></item><item><title>Copy Unblocker - A Userscript to Remove Website Copy Restrictions</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2025/userscript-copy-unblocker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 13:36:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2025/userscript-copy-unblocker/</guid><description>A userscript that removes copy restrictions from various websites. This article details the installation process of Copy Unblocker, its main features, and how to extend support for more websites. No programming knowledge required - enable free copying of web content in just a few simple steps.</description></item><item><title>Multilingual Hugo Blog - How to Elegantly Manage Markdown Content</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2024/hugo-multilingual-blog-structure/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 11:04:39 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2024/hugo-multilingual-blog-structure/</guid><description>This article discusses file organization strategies for multilingual Hugo sites, URL structure optimization, and how to safely migrate existing blog content. It&amp;rsquo;s a useful reference for Hugo users looking to build multilingual blogs.</description></item><item><title>Hugo-Theme-Jane V3 Major Update</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2024/hugo-theme-jane-v3-major-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 06:56:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2024/hugo-theme-jane-v3-major-update/</guid><description>Hugo theme Jane releases V3 major update, introducing Pico CSS color system with dark mode support, new custom homepage functionality, and STYLE SETTINGS for personalization. This update focuses on enhancing user experience and customization needs while maintaining simplicity, allowing users to focus more on writing.</description></item><item><title>Swapping Ctrl and CapsLock Keys in Windows</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2022/windows-keyboard-remap-ctrl-capslock-powershell/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2022/windows-keyboard-remap-ctrl-capslock-powershell/</guid><description>Learn how to easily swap Ctrl and CapsLock keys in Windows using a simple PowerShell script to enhance keyboard efficiency. This guide provides complete configuration steps that work permanently without additional software. Perfect for programmers and power keyboard users.</description></item></channel></rss>