<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Career Change on Xianmin's Blog</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/tags/career-change/</link><description>Recent content in Career Change on Xianmin's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 06:13:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.xianmin.org/en/tags/career-change/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Weekly Journal of a 33-Year-Old Unemployed Rural Programmer's Self-Help Journey (4) - AI Efficiency, Income ¥1410</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/004/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 05:50:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/004/</guid><description>This article chronicles the self-help journey of a 33-year-old unemployed rural programmer. Through freelance projects including enterprise spreadsheet automation and Vue to React conversion, leveraging AI tools to improve work efficiency, he completed 8 orders earning ¥1410 in one week. The article shares experiences in remote freelancing, AI-assisted programming insights, and the importance of building client relationships, providing reference for programmers aspiring to freelance work.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Journal of a 33-year-old Unemployed Rural Programmer's Self-Help Journey (3) - Finding My Position</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/003/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 14:41:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/weekly/003/</guid><description>This article documents the third week of a 33-year-old unemployed rural programmer&amp;rsquo;s self-help journey. The author achieved weekly earnings over 1000 yuan through freelancing and established his position as a &amp;rsquo;technical handyman&amp;rsquo;. The article shares failed cases in remote printing and web development, summarizes experiences in efficient communication, improving speech skills, and pricing strategies, and displays real freelancing income details. This is a valuable experience sharing for programmers who want to achieve freelance work through technical skills.</description></item></channel></rss>