<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tech on Xianmin's Blog</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/categories/tech/</link><description>Recent content in Tech on Xianmin's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 01:36:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.xianmin.org/en/categories/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Git Archive: Practical Guide for Efficient Packaging and Project Delivery</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2025/git-archive-tutorial-project-packaging/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 10:00:56 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2025/git-archive-tutorial-project-packaging/</guid><description>Git Archive: A powerful tool for efficiently packaging source code, making project delivery more professional. This article details how to use the git archive command to automatically exclude the .git directory and files in .gitignore, eliminating the need for manual filtering and generating clean project archives with a single command. Includes a useful PowerShell function that helps Windows users easily create standardized release packages. Compared to traditional compression tools, git archive is not only more efficient but also ensures consistency and professionalism in code delivery. An essential project delivery skill for developers.</description></item><item><title>Why I Choose Vivaldi as My Primary Browser</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2025/why-choose-vivaldi-browser-vs-chrome/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 12:57:01 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2025/why-choose-vivaldi-browser-vs-chrome/</guid><description>As a Chromium-based browser, Vivaldi not only offers perfect compatibility with Chrome extensions but also provides more user-friendly interface customization, powerful tab management, multi-page tiling, and other unique features. This article compares the user experience between Vivaldi and Chrome in detail to help you find the most suitable primary browser.</description></item><item><title>Copy Unblocker - A Userscript to Remove Website Copy Restrictions</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2025/userscript-copy-unblocker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 13:36:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2025/userscript-copy-unblocker/</guid><description>A userscript that removes copy restrictions from various websites. This article details the installation process of Copy Unblocker, its main features, and how to extend support for more websites. No programming knowledge required - enable free copying of web content in just a few simple steps.</description></item><item><title>Multilingual Hugo Blog - How to Elegantly Manage Markdown Content</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2024/hugo-multilingual-blog-structure/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 11:04:39 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2024/hugo-multilingual-blog-structure/</guid><description>This article discusses file organization strategies for multilingual Hugo sites, URL structure optimization, and how to safely migrate existing blog content. It&amp;rsquo;s a useful reference for Hugo users looking to build multilingual blogs.</description></item><item><title>Hugo-Theme-Jane V3 Major Update</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2024/hugo-theme-jane-v3-major-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 06:56:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2024/hugo-theme-jane-v3-major-update/</guid><description>Hugo theme Jane releases V3 major update, introducing Pico CSS color system with dark mode support, new custom homepage functionality, and STYLE SETTINGS for personalization. This update focuses on enhancing user experience and customization needs while maintaining simplicity, allowing users to focus more on writing.</description></item><item><title>Swapping Ctrl and CapsLock Keys in Windows</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2022/windows-keyboard-remap-ctrl-capslock-powershell/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2022/windows-keyboard-remap-ctrl-capslock-powershell/</guid><description>Learn how to easily swap Ctrl and CapsLock keys in Windows using a simple PowerShell script to enhance keyboard efficiency. This guide provides complete configuration steps that work permanently without additional software. Perfect for programmers and power keyboard users.</description></item></channel></rss>