<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tech on Xianmin's Blog</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/categories/tech/</link><description>Recent content in Tech on Xianmin's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 13:36:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.xianmin.org/en/categories/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Copy Unblocker - A Userscript to Remove Website Copy Restrictions</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2025/userscript-copy-unblocker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 13:36:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2025/userscript-copy-unblocker/</guid><description>A userscript that removes copy restrictions from various websites. This article details the installation process of Copy Unblocker, its main features, and how to extend support for more websites. No programming knowledge required - enable free copying of web content in just a few simple steps.</description></item><item><title>Multilingual Hugo Blog - How to Elegantly Manage Markdown Content</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2024/hugo-multilingual-blog-structure/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 11:04:39 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2024/hugo-multilingual-blog-structure/</guid><description>This article discusses file organization strategies for multilingual Hugo sites, URL structure optimization, and how to safely migrate existing blog content. It&amp;rsquo;s a useful reference for Hugo users looking to build multilingual blogs.</description></item><item><title>Hugo-Theme-Jane V3 Major Update</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2024/hugo-theme-jane-v3-major-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 06:56:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2024/hugo-theme-jane-v3-major-update/</guid><description>Hugo theme Jane releases V3 major update, introducing Pico CSS color system with dark mode support, new custom homepage functionality, and STYLE SETTINGS for personalization. This update focuses on enhancing user experience and customization needs while maintaining simplicity, allowing users to focus more on writing.</description></item><item><title>Swapping Ctrl and CapsLock Keys in Windows</title><link>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2022/windows-keyboard-remap-ctrl-capslock-powershell/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xianmin.org/en/post/2022/windows-keyboard-remap-ctrl-capslock-powershell/</guid><description>Learn how to easily swap Ctrl and CapsLock keys in Windows using a simple PowerShell script to enhance keyboard efficiency. This guide provides complete configuration steps that work permanently without additional software. Perfect for programmers and power keyboard users.</description></item></channel></rss>